The primary way that a user interacts with a native app is through touch.
用户与原生应用互动的主要方式是通过触摸进行互动
So we want to make sure that we have the proper buttons and
因此我们要确保提供正确的按钮和组件
the proper components to handle any touch events that we get specifically,
以对任何触摸事件做出响应
to respond to things like button clicks.
具体而言 对按钮点击做出响应
So, what react-native gives us is four different components.
react-native 提供了四种不同的组件
They are TouchableHighlight, TouchableNativeFeedback,
分别为 TouchableHighlight TouchableNativeFeedback
TouchableOpacity and TouchableWithoutFeedback in order to respond to these presses,
TouchableOpacity 和 TouchableWithoutFeedback
to these button presses.
以便对这些按钮点击操作做出响应
So what we'll do is walk through each of these.
我们将介绍每种组件
So first, let's start off with TouchableHighlight.
首先介绍 TouchableHighlight
What TouchableHighlight is going to do,
TouchableHighlight 的作用是
is it's going to basically transform from
当你点击按钮时
its primary color to another color when you press on it.
它会使按钮从主颜色变成另一种颜色
So what we'll do and we also down here have some styles our container,
在下面有一些样式容器
just a normal button and then the button text.
包括普通按钮和按钮文本
So what we can do here is,
在这里
we can add our button styles to this component.
我们可以向此组件添加按钮样式
And then what we want to say is,
然后输入 onPress
on press go ahead and run the handle press method right here.
并运行这里的 handlePress 方法
And then lastly, what we want to do is we want to specify
最后指定 underlayColor
an underlay color which is going to be the color
也就是按钮背景
that the background of the button transforms to.
所变成的颜色
So we'll just come in here and say #d4271B,
输入 #d4271b
which is just a dark red color because our normal button is this color.
也就是深红色 因为普通按钮是这个颜色
So now inside of here,
在这里面
we can pass it whatever we want the button to display.
我们可以传入希望按钮显示的内容
Let's just say TouchableHighlight and then we will give this a style of styles.btnText.
输入 Touchable Highlight 然后设定样式 styles.btnText
So now if we look at our app,
现在查看应用
you'll notice that we have this button.
会看到这个按钮
And when we press on it,
点击该按钮
you'll notice it gets a little bit darker because what's happening,
你会发现背景色稍微变深了
is we are going from our background color to this underlay color.
因为我们从背景色变成了铺垫颜色
So you can see this on iOS as well.
在 iOS 应用中也是这种效果
So that is TouchableHighlight.
这就是 TouchableHighlight 组件的作用
The next one, let's talk about TouchableOpacity.
下一个将是 TouchableOpacity
I actually really like TouchableOpacity,
我实际上很喜欢 TouchableOpacity 组件
it's probably my favorite.
可能是我最喜欢的组件
So what we can do is we can get rid of
我们将删掉这里的 underlayColor
this underlay color here so we don't have to worry about that.
不用考虑它了
And now what's going to happen,
现在
is when we press on this,
当我们点击此按钮时
you'll notice the opacity of the button is just going to change.
你会发现按钮的透明度变化了
So that way the background is going to shine through.
也就是透出背景色
So TouchableOpacity again just changes the opacity of the button,
TouchableOpacity 会改变按钮的透明度
so that the background can shine through a little bit.
使背景色更突出
Next, TouchableWithoutFeedback basically doesn't
接着是 TouchableWithoutFeedback
change the button at all when you click on it.
当你点击按钮时 它基本上不会改变按钮外观
And what's different about this one is it doesn't work with text,
它的区别在于不适用于文本
so you actually need to go ahead and have a view as the only child.
设定一个唯一子级 View
And then we'll take our style from the TouchableWithoutFeedback and put it on the view,
然后获取 TouchableWithoutFeedback 上的样式并放在该 View 上
and then now what's going to happen is
现在
notice when I press this, so I'm pressing right now.
当我点击该按钮时
Nothing is happening because we're getting no feedback.
什么也没发生 因为我们没有获得任何反馈
This one probably shouldn't be used too much because
该组件最好别使用
native is all about giving feedback to the user.
因为原生应用就是要向用户提供反馈
But in some cases, it is helpful.
但在某些情况下 它也很有用
And now the last one we're going to look at is TouchableNativeFeedback.
最后我们将讨论 TouchableNativeFeedback
This one isn't supported on iOS,
此组件在 iOS 上不受支持
it's only supported on Android.
仅适用于 Android
And what it does is it gives that button that ripple effect,
它将使按钮出现涟漪效果
which is native to the Android platform.
该效果是 Android 平台的原生效果
So what we can say is we can come in here and add a background prop to this.
我们可以在这里面添加背景属性
We'll say background equals and then
输入 background =
we will say touchablenativefeedback.selectablebackground.
然后输入 TouchableNativeFeedback.SelectableBackground
And one thing about TouchableNativeFeedback too,
对于 TouchableNativeFeedback 还需要注意一点
is it also doesn't work with text as its child,
它不能将 Text 作为其子级
so you need to have you as well.
因此需要变成 View
So now, if we look at this,
现在你会发现
you'll notice that on iOS it's stirring an error because it's not supported,
在 iOS 上出现了错误 因为该组件不适用于 iOS 平台
but on Android, you get rid of this hello so we can see this.
但是在 on Android 上 删掉这个 hello 提示
You'll notice that when I click on it,
这样就能看清效果 点击该按钮
we get that cool little ripple effect.
出现了很酷的涟漪效果